Guide to the Junior League of Brooklyn records ARC.304
Brooklyn Historical Society
- Series 8: Printed Materials, 1920-2000
  - What Works: Association of Junior Leagues publication, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 10)
  - Brooklyn Daily Eagle (2 folders)(Dec. 3, 1930) (Box 45, Folder -)
  - Newspaper clipping from Sanitary Fair (5 folders), 1930 (Box 45, Folder -)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1920-1939 (Box 25, Folder 11)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1940-1949 (Box 25, Folder 12)
  - Newspaper clippings (1), 1950-1959 (Box 25, Folder 13)
  - Newspaper clippings (2), 1950-1959 (Box 25, Folder 14)
  - Newspaper clippings (3), 1950-1959 (Box 25, Folder 15)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1960-1969 (Box 25, Folder 16)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1970-1989 (Box 25, Folder 17)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1990-1993 (Box 25, Folder 18)
- Series 9: Scrapbooks, 1925-1978
  The series consists of unbound scrapbook leaves and loose documents in folders, and oversized scrapbooks with original covers. Oversized items are housed in two flat boxes. Materials found in the scrapbooks include press clippings that were either glued or taped onto leaves, photographs, handwritten annotations, correspondence, event invitations and fliers, awards, and newsletters.
  - Scrapbook, 1925-1927 (Box 25, Folder 19)
  - Scrapbook leaves, 1928 (Box 25, Folder 20)
  - Scrapbook, 1927-1931 (Box 46, Folder -)
  - Scrapbook leaves, 1931-1932 (Box 25, Folder 21)
  - Scrapbook leaves and related materials (oversized), 1932 (Box 45, Folder -)
  - Scrapbook leaves, 1932-1933 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - Scrapbook leaves, 1934-1935 (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - Scrapbook leaves, 1935-1936 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Scrapbook leaves, 1939 (Box 26, Folder 4)
  - Scrapbook leaves, 1942-1943 (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Scrapbook leaves, 1939 (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Children's theatre scrapbook: Original (oversized), 1933-1953 (Box 41, Folder -)
  - Children's theatre scrapbook: copies, 1933-1953 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - Scrapbook, 1970-1971 (Box 43, Folder -)
  - Scrapbook for Underground Society Bash, 1977 (Box 43, Folder -)
  - Scrapbook (oversized), 1935-1940 (Box 41, Folder -)
  - Scrapbook (oversized), 1970-1978 (Box 41, Folder -)
  - Scrapbook leaves (oversized), 1936, 1938 (Box 41, Folder -)
  - Scrapbook leaves (oversized), 1957-1958 (Box 41, Folder -)
  - Scrapbook (oversized), 1956-1958 (Box 41, Folder -)
  - Scrapbook (oversized), 1935-1940 (Box 39, Folder -)
  - Scrapbook (oversized), 1960 (Box 39, Folder -)
  - Scrapbook materials, 1982-2000 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    General
    This file contains items that were loosely placed between the pages of a scrapbook that was in very poor condition. The photographs from this scrapbook are located in Series 10: Photographs, Sub-series 2: Events, members, and service projects, file "Scrapbook photographs."
- Series 10: Photographs, Negatives, and Slides, 1910-2000; 1980-1995; 0 Linear Feet
  Series 10 consists of two sub-series housed in three manuscript boxes, one oversize box, one photo box, and one slide box.
  Sub-series 1, Exhibition Photographs, contains approximately forty enlarged and mounted photographs depicting significant League events and service projects, dating between 1940 and 1989. These photographs were exhibited at an unknown League event and are approximately 5" by 7" and 8" by 10" in size (not including matting or mounting board).
  Sub-series 2, Members, Events, and Service Projects, consists of photographs, negatives, and slides of League members, events, and service projects. There are approximately sixty negatives and negative strips, twenty-five loose 8" by 10" photographs, 650 loose photographs (mostly 4" by 6" size), and ninety-four slides.
  Arrangement
  Series 10 is divided into two sub-series.
  - Sub-series 1: Exhibition Photographs, 1940-1989
    Series 10, sub-series 1, Exhibition Photographs, contains approximately forty enlarged and mounted photographs depicting significant League events and service projects, dating between 1940 and 1989. These photographs were exhibited at an unknown League event and are approximately 5" by 7" and 8" by 10" in size (not including matting or mounting board). There are two manuscript boxes and one oversize box. Notable items include photographs portraying award presentations to the League, including the Presidential Recognition Award in 1983, the Eleanor Roosevelt Community Service Award for the League's work with Court Appointed Special Advocates (CASA), circa 1990s, and a Parenting Education Project grant presentation in 1984. There are also photographs of League fundraising events, including the Underground Society Bash at the New York Transit Museum in Brooklyn, 1977, and Champagne Gala fundraiser in 1988.
    - Toy Workshop toy drive, circa 1970; black and white print, mounted (Box 32, Folder -)
    - Parenting Education Project grant presentation, 1984; black and white print, mounted (Box 32, Folder -)
      Neita Loy Blondeau Montague
    - Health and Safety Awareness Day at LIU, 1985; black and white print, mounted (Box 32, Folder -)
    - Operation Breakfast, Fort Greene, 1971; black and white print, mounted (Box 32, Folder -)
    - Senior Citizen Action Desk, 1978; black and white print, mounted (Box 32, Folder -)
    - Presidential Recognition Award Presentation, 1983; two black and white prints, mounted, mounted caption (Box 32, Folder -)
      Neita Loy Blondeau Montague accepting award. Also pictures Joseph Montieciolo, Regional Administrator of the Department of Housing and Urban Development, and Dr. Bernard Kilbourn, Regional Director of the Department of Health and Human Services.
    - Board of Directors, 1989; black and white print, mounted (Box 32, Folder -)
    - Connie Reich with young hospital patient, circa 1960; black and white print, mounted (Box 32, Folder -)
    - Committee to Celebrate Brooklyn Historical Society's 125th Anniversary, 1989; black and white print, mounted (Box 32, Folder -)
    - Project Reach Youth, Park Slope, circa 1980; two black and white prints, one mounted with caption on reverse side, one matted (Box 32, Folder -)
    - Underground Society Bash fundraiser, 1977; two black and white prints, mounted, captions on reverse sides, one black and white print, matted (Box 32, Folder -)
      Event located at New York Transit Museum in Brooklyn.
    - Champagne Gala fundraiser, 1988; three black and white photos, matted (Box 32, Folder -)
    - Theatre Productions: "The Plain Princess", circa 1940; black and white print, mounted, with printed caption at bottom (Box 33, Folder -)
      Sue Blum, Anne Moore, Nancy Pearsall, Narcissa Titman, Jeni Blair, Elinore Bachman
    - Women's Survival Space, child's poem, circa 1990; Typed poem, mounted, authored by "Rosy, Age 9" (Box 33, Folder -)
    - Senior Citizens Radio Show, 1985; black and white print, matted, separate mounted caption (Box 33, Folder -)
    - Opening meeting, 1988; black and white print, mounted (Box 33, Folder -)
      President Christine Nevin presiding over opening meeting
    - Gateway Gala, 1981; black and white print, matted (Box 33, Folder -)
    - "Professional Women in the 80's" Forum, 1982; black and white print, mounted, with mounted caption (Box 33, Folder -)
      Carol Jenkins, NBC-TV news anchor. Neita Loy Blondeau Montague.
    - "Celebrating 80 Years of Service" poster, 1990 (Box 36, Folder -)
    - JLB Funds, Neonatal at Cumberland Medical Center, 1967 (Box 36, Folder -)
    - Eleanore Roosevelt Community Service Award, Court Appointed Special Advocates (CASA), circa 1990 (Box 36, Folder -)
      Sarah Kennedy holding medal
    - Informational poster, Community Boards with JLB representatives, circa 1990 (Box 36, Folder -)
      Presidential Recognition Award, Neita Blondeau, Neighborhood Family Services Coalition, New York City Self-Help Clearinghouse, Long Island College Hospital Associate Board
    - WNYE-TV Channel 25, circa 1980 (Box 36, Folder -)
    - Mentoring, circa 1980 (Box 36, Folder -)
    - Fundraiser, 1962 (Box 36, Folder -)
    - Informational Poster, Court Appointed Special Advocates, circa 1990 (Box 36, Folder -)
  - Sub-series 2: Members, Events, and Service Projects, 1900-2000
    Series 10, sub-series 2, Members, Events, and Service Projects, consists of photographs, negatives, and slides of League members, events, and service projects. These are housed in one manuscript box, one photo box, and one slide box. This sub-series notably includes photographs of past League presidents and founding women, dating from the early 1900s to the 1990s, including a photograph of Harriet Barnes Pratt, League founder and president from 1911 to 1913. Enlarged prints show unidentified theatrical productions dating from 1930 to circa 1960s, with people in elaborate costumes. Other enlargements dating between 1910 and 1950 show women in fashionable clothing, furs, and hats, including one photograph depicting a fashion show in 1953, with women in previous decades' fashions. There are a large number of smaller prints representing Provisional classes, members at meetings and events, and notable service projects, such as Long Island College Hospital (LICH) Children's Story Hour, a Toy Workshop toy drive, Hug a Baby, Parenting Education Program, and projects at the Crown Heights Youth Collective. Smaller prints also depict fundraising events, such as the Hemisphere Ball in 1962, the League's 85th Anniversary Ball, and an unknown formal event at the Marriott Hotel, circa 1990s.
    - Past presidents and founding women (6 folders), circa 1910-1990; various sizes, up to 8"x10" (Box 33, Folder 1-6)
      Alletta L. Dening Crane, Frances J. Douglass Kerby, Annie-Lee Duncan Kerst, Elinore Lincoln Bachman, Neita Loy Blondeau Montague, Nancy Boden Pearsall, Leonore Caldwell Woodcock, Gail Donovan, Ann Chalfant Ellis, Michele Brouillard Flynn, Mary Jane Harris, Harriette Heller, Natalie Stanton Kennedy, Dona Laughlin, Julie Dozier Nelson, Deirdre Colby Sato, Debra Smallwood, Marcia L. Smith, Mary Noyes Spelman, Helen Spontak, Joanne L. Steward Woodfin, Mrs. Hollis K. Thayer, Mrs. Oscar P. Schoenemann, Mrs. John M. Beers, Mrs. John H. Livingston, Mrs. William G. James, Mrs. Philip F. Mygatt, Harriet Barnes Pratt, E.B. Thayer McKee, Agnes Thompson Verrill, Virginia Mollenhauer Maynard, Emily Goetz, Mary Osborn Polak Oenslager, Esther Baldwin Bromley, Virginia Fuller Francis, Grace Love Blust, Jane Smith Bonynge, Janet Sweet Sanborn.
    - Scrapbook photographs, 1980s (Box 31, Folder -)
      Removed from poor condition scrapbook. Documents from same scrapbook are located in Series 9: Scrapbooks, file "Scrapbook materials." In-League Fundraiser Spring 1980, Claudia Benzenberg, Ginny Gleichman, Dwight Ellis, Susan Kilborn, Gail Grossman, Mary Lou Wells, Susan Skerritt, Claudia Barber, Kate Firth, Eileen Aird, John Wells, Lynn Rutan(?), Addie Rosen, John Gleason, Bryce Sanders, Chris McKay. AJL Annual Meeting, May 1983, Dallas, Texas. The Big D Ranch. Pat Vitacco, Marianne Decker, Christine McLaughlin, Laurel Whitaker, Susan Kilborn, Kay Desai at unknown event.
    - Theatrical productions, 1930-circa 1960s (Box 31, Folder -)
      Children's theater, Hansel & Gretel, 1930. Photo credit Jay Sharp. Various unidentified theatrical productions.
    - Events, members, service projects (4 folders), circa 1940s-2000 (Box 31, Folder 1-4)
      Virginia Lee Comer, Helen Creamer, Mrs. Newton D. Crane, photo credit Martin Candids. Children's hospital theatre marionette/puppet performance, circa 1960s, Mrs. Thomas Blankley, Mrs. Charles Stern, Mrs. O. Taft Nelson, Janie Cook, Donald Clark, Richard Jackson, Rhea Collins, photo credit Publicity Photographers. JLB Fashion Show 1953, Mrs. Richard Shaffer, Ann Winslow, Patricia Foote, Mrs. David Bush, Mrs. Paul Bonynge, Jr., depicting women's hats and fashion from 1910-1950. Ann Clausen, Claudia Barber. Holiday Gala 1990. Project Reach Youth. Long Island College Hospital (LICH) Children's Story Hour, 1988-1989. Hug A Baby, 1990. Parenting Education Program. Neita Loy Blondeau Montague and small plane, 1998. Brooklyn Bridge Centennial, 1983. JLB Dapper Dan, 1984. Julie Dozier Nelson. Brooklyn Academy of Music (BAM) President Harvey Lichtenstein. Photo credits Deborah Gardner, Tom Callan, and Rob Kinmonth. Underground Society Bash, 1977 at New York Transit Museum in Brooklyn. AJL Annual Conference, 1977-1978, Ann Ellis. Photo credit Cliff Kalick Photography. Provisional Bank Party, December 1978. Free Lunch Program. Selma Fink teaching sculpture to the blind at Industrial Home for the Blind. Provisionals at the Hemisphere Ball, 1962. F. Thayer, E. Flickinger, W. Lewis, Moore. Connie Reich with young hospital patient. Students studying, tutoring. Toy Workshop toy drive. Brooklyn Children's Museum.
    - Events, members, service projects (photo box), 1980s-2000s (Box 34, Folder -)
      League members circa 1980-2000. JL-NYSPAC conference, March 1982. Presidential Recap Awards, May 1983. Unknown events, 1980s-2000s. Scrapbook photos, 1982-1983 including AJLI Conference; July Board meeting at Ann Heilakka's; JLB Annual Meeting 1982; Opening meeting, September 1983; May Picnic; House Tour Day volunteers; Board dinner at Barbara Moore's, June 1982. Board training circa 1990s. Quilting story circa 1990s. Provisionals circa 1990s. Headshots circa 1990s, Michele Brouillard Flynn, Xanthe Effros Kaldis. Crown Heights Youth Collective, circa 1990s. Crown Heights Health Fair, circa 1990s. Ellen Chesler Lecture at Brooklyn Historical Society, circa 1990s. Unknown event at Marriott Hotel, circa 1990s. JLB Cruise, April 1992. Bates Youth Conference, 1992. Brooklyn Friends School, circa 1992. AJLI Annual Conference, 1993. Placement Fair, 1993. Sustainer Tea at Selma Fink's, 1993. JLB Fundraiser, 1993. Bates Youth Fest, 1994. Crown Heights Youth Collective book drive at Brooklyn Historical Society. 85th Anniversary Ball. Silent Witness March in New Jersey, 1995. Women's Survival Space and Court Appointed Special Advocates (CASA), circa 1990-2000. JLB March for Breast Cancer, circa 1990-2000. Diads, circa 2000s.
    - Events and corresponding negatives, 1971-1989 (Box 31, Folder -)
      Each black and white 5"x7" print is accompanied by an approx. 4"x5" negative. Photo credit Deborah Gardner. Operation Breakfast, Fort Greene, 1971; Opening JLB meeting, 1988; Health and Safety Awareness Day, LIU, 1985; Board members 1988-1989; Committee to Celebrate Brooklyn Historical Society's 125th Anniversary, 1989; Parenting Education Project grant presentation, 1984; Senior Citizen Action Desk, 1978; "Professional Women in the 80s" Forum, 1982.
    - Negatives, circa 1960s-2000s (Box 31, Folder -)
      Negative strips and 4"x5" negatives for Brooklyn Children's Museum circa 1990s, Parenting Education Project Grant Presentation 1984, AJLI conference circa 1990s, Placement Fair 1993, Ellen Chesler Lecture at Brooklyn Historical Society circa 1990s, Bates Youth Conference 1992, JLB Fundraiser 1993, Past Presidents 1911-circa 2000, unknown event at Marriott Hotel circa 1990s, "Plain Princess" theater production circa 1960s, Neita Blondeau accepting "Exemplary Community Service" award 1983, Long Island College Hospital (LICH) Children's Story Hour 1988, Judy Stutt and friends playing checkers circa 1990s, Connie Reich and patient circa 1960s, Toy Workshop toy drive circa 1970s, other unknown events circa 1980-1990. Four printed pages from negative strips, unknown event (possibly a holiday party) and unknown meeting.
    - "A Tribute to AJL's History" script, 1984 (Box 31, Folder -)
      Accompanies "A Tribute to AJL's History" slide show, 77 slides, located in Series 10, sub-series 2, file "Educational and Event Slides."
    - Educational and event slides, 1984, circa 1980 (Box 35, Folder -)
      Parenting Education slide show, fourteen slides. "A Tribute to AJL's History" slide show, May 1984, seventy-seven slides, script located in Series 10, Sub-Series 2, file "'A Tribute to AJL's History' script." Hot Breakfast and Landlord Program, circa 1970s, five slides.
    - Photo Album, 1970s (Box 30, Folder 1)
- Series 11: Artifacts, 1985-2000
  - Lenox orchid from AJLI, 1981 (Box 38, Folder -)
  - 75th anniversary pins, 1985 (Box 26, Folder 1)
  - JLB pins, undated (Box 26, Folder 2)
  - "Welcome Back to Brooklyn" tag, 1988 (Box 26, Folder 3)
  - Creative Public Relations Award – AJLI, undated (Box 26, Folder 5)
  - Recognition plaque – Safe Horizons, undated (Box 26, Folder 6)
  - Resolution of Thanks – Assoc. for Crippled Children and Adults, 1972 (Box 26, Folder 7)
  - 70 Years Commemorative plaque – Howard Golden, Brooklyn Borough President, 1980 (Box 26, Folder 8)
  - Ecumenical Service Award (plaque) – Brooklyn Council of Churches, 1990 (Box 26, Folder 9)
  - Special Recognition Award (plaque) – United States Congress, 1993 (Box 26, Folder 10)
  - Legislative Resolutions – New York State Senate, 1993-1998 (Box 26, Folder 11)
  - Communications Award – AJLI, 1994 (Box 26, Folder 12)
  - Recognition plaque – Collective Fellowship and Peace Academy, 1995 (Box 26, Folder 13)
  - Certificate of Appreciation – Brooklyn Bureau of Community Service, 1998 (Box 26, Folder 14)
  - Prime Time Radio safeties, 3131-A and 3131-B, magnetic (2), 1985 (Box 37, Folder -)
  - "Parliamentary Procedures Demystified," audiocassette, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 15)
  - "Marilyn Falls: Finance," audiocassette, 1991 (Box 26, Folder 16)
  - AJLI 76th Annual Conference, audiocassette (2), undated (Box 26, Folder 17)
  - "Panel on Women" and "Women and Alcohol," audiocassette (2), undated (Box 26, Folder 18)
  - "Silent Witness," audiocassette, undated (Box 26, Folder 19)
  - "Women: Time for Self," audiocassette, undated (Box 26, Folder 20)
  - Training Tapes, audiocassettes (6), undated (Box 26, Folder 21)
  - Training Tapes, audiocassettes (4), undated (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - CBS Sunday Morning, video, 1982 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - "Sunday Morning" spot, video, 1982 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - "80th Annual Message," VHS, 1990 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Public service announcement, Umatic video, 1994 (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - "Sharing a Passion for Excellence," VHS, 1998 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - "IMAGINE," Brooklyn Psychiatric Centers, VHS, 2001 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - "Women of Vision," New York Junior League, VHS, 2001 (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - AJLI Centennial celebration, VHS, 2001 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Brooklyn Child Advocacy Center (BCAC), VHS (2), undated (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - "Greetings from Brooklyn," VHS, undated (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - JLB Leadership Training, video, undated (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - "Popcorn," ZEA, VHS, undated (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - "Power of Association," AJLI, VHS, undated (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - "Power of Association," AJLI, VHS (2), undated (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - "Project: Response to Rape," VHS (2), undated (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - "Project: Response to Rape," VHS (2), undated (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - "Restoring Dignity," VHS (2), undated (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - "Very Special Arts," Amway Corporation, VHS, undated (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - "Woman to Woman" public service announcements, magnetic (2), undated (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - "Woman to Woman" public service announcements, magnetic large, undated (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - "Woman to Woman" public service announcements, magnetic large, undated (Box 29, Folder 11)